# Amalina Hashim | Innovation & Digital Experience Strategist

mobile: +65 91466330 | email: <a href="mailto:amalinazafirahashim@gmail.com">amalinazafirahashim@gmail.com</a> | personal website: <a href="https://my-website-iota-nine.vercel.app/">https://my-website-iota-nine.vercel.app/</a> | linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/amalina-hashim-75644bb7">https://www.linkedin.com/in/amalina-hashim-75644bb7</a> | github: <a href="https://github.com/Amalina-Hashim">https://github.com/Amalina-Hashim</a>

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

My Total years working in the tech industry: more than 8 years, My Gender: female, My Age: 41 years old, Number of siblings I have: 1 older brother who is a secondary school teacher, My Nationality/ Citizenship: Singaporean, My Address: NorthEast of Singapore, Punggol, My Favourite colour: black, white, pink, My Favourite food: mom's home cooked meals. Including but not limited to Traditional malay cuisine, Italian, Japanese and Thai, My Favourite bands/ musicians: Includes but not limited to Iron Maiden, Metallica, UFO, Jimi Hendrix, Led Zeppelin, Band-Maid, Bear vs Shark, Between The Buried and Me, Marilyn Manson, The Smashing Pumpkins, The Stray Cats, The Living End and many more, My Hobbies: reading, streaming movies, documentaries and podcasts, playing the guitar, bass and ukulele

## **CAREER PROFILE/ AREAS OF INTEREST**

"As a practised Innovation and Digital Transformation Strategist, I specialise in leading cross-functional teams through the lifecycle of complex digital projects from ideation to implementation. Understanding technology's role in creating business value, I enjoy driving initiatives that harness cloud solutions, artificial intelligence, and user-centric design to address business challenges and enhance customer experiences. Committed to lifelong learning and innovation, I continuously explore new technologies to push the boundaries of what is possible."

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Design Thinking and Rapid Prototyping
- User Experience and Service Design
- Digital Product and Platform Management
- Debugging and troubleshooting
- Cloud Solutions Integrations and Deployment
- Agile and Scrum Project Management
- Strategic Business Analysis and Data Insights

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Full Stack Software Engineering (ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Python, Django).
- Cloud Solutions (Google, Azure, AWS)
- Data Analysis (Power Bl, Tableau, SQL, R)
- Project Management (Jira, Trello, Asana)
- Microsoft Office Suite

## **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Successful deployment of the Receipt Data Capturing System and POS Enhancement solutions for HPB's Eat Drink Shop Healthy Campaign with over 20,000 touchpoints.
- Inaugural launch of Eunoia's Go Digital Platform with key features including rapid Go Live, Payments, CRM, POS, Delivery and other 3rd-party integrations.
- Central Ops implementation of the Youth Olympic Games 2010 Catering Meals Ordering System serving over 7000 athletes, officials and staff.

#### RECENT SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

- Geopayment System: a geofencing payment system designed for use at event spaces, carparks, gyms etc. Technologies used: Python, Django, ReactJS, Google APIs, Stripe APIs, Google Cloud Solutions.
- eCommerce Platform: End-to-End online shopping platform with Products management, Cart, Favourites and Payment features. Technologies used: Javascript, ReactJS, Express, MongoDB, Stripe APIs, Vercel and Render.
- Al Fruit Journal: A mobile camera Al integrated image detection fruit journal. Technologies used: ReactJS, Google Maps APIs, Clarifai, Airtable, Cloudinary and Vercel.

View Portfolio here.

## PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

# Manager, Healthy Food & Dining (Planning & Strategy Team)

Health Promotion Board | June 2019 - September 2023

- Led business development and digital transformation projects, enhancing organisational performance and productivity using agile methodologies.
- Directed technology projects (e.g. Eat Drink Shop Healthy, Internal Systems Enhancements, Partner POS
  Integrations etc.) to streamline and improve internal systems, enhancing interoperability and user experience.
- Analysed data to provide insights for decision-making, led annual work planning with agile principles, and co-created the division's 5-year strategic plans and budgets.

#### **Product Manager**

Eunoia Pte Ltd | August 2017 - June 2019

- Led the rapid development and deployment of digital ordering platforms, reducing go-live times from weeks to days and directly supporting business scalability.
- Developed and integrated comprehensive digital solutions with CRM, POS and other 3rd party systems, increasing operational efficiency and user satisfaction.
- Strategized and developed the product roadmap leading the UX and Development teams through the milestones to successful feature deployments.
- Ensured testing protocols and proactive bug management, maintaining product quality.

#### **Business Designer**

Eunoia Pte Ltd | Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

- Led technology innovation projects in the F&B industry, enhancing productivity and service satisfaction through human-centred design.
- Applied Design Thinking for user experience design and prototyping, delivering actionable insights and innovative solutions.
- Developed and deployed custom digital solutions for brands like Alt. Pizza and Artisan Boulangerie Co., including multi-platform applications and robust order/content management systems.

## **EDUCATION**

- Software Engineering General Assembly, June 2024
- MEng, Innovation by Design Singapore University of Technology & Design, Singapore, December 2021
- Specialisation in Digital Manufacturing Design & Technology University at Buffalo, Coursera, December 2019
- Specialist Diploma in Design Strategy & Management (Innovation) Nanyang Polytechnic, Singapore, December 2018
- BSc Food Science University of Otago, New Zealand, August 2006

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- NUS Digital Product Management
- Certified Scrum Master
- Leading SAFe Agilist 6.0
- Figma UI Design
- Google Analytics Professional Certificate
- Data Analytics with Excel
- Power BI